Guide to the Kathryn Diehl Riot Grrrl Collection MSS 448
Fales Library and Special Collections
Kathryn Diehl Riot Grrrl Collection
1992-1996
MSS 448
Fales Library and Special Collections
0.5 linear feet in 1 manuscript box
Kathryn Diehl is a Los Angeles-based audio engineer who was actively involved in the punk, hardcore, and Riot Grrrl scenes in both Washington, D.C. and Richmond, Virginia. This collection consists of materials created and collected by Diehl from the early to mid-1990s documenting her participation in the Riot Grrrl movement, including newsletters; Riot Grrrl zines; flyers for shows in the Washington, D.C. and Richmond, Virginia areas; and letters to Diehl from individuals such as Kathleen Hanna, Lisa Wildman, and Tobi Vail, predominantly on the subject of Diehl’s zines. The collection also includes masters and copies of Diehl’s own zines Moonfork and Oppression.
Diehl, Kathryn
Biographical/Historical note
Kathryn Diehl is an audio engineer who was actively involved in the punk, hardcore, and Riot Grrrl scenes in both Washington, D.C. and Richmond, Virginia. As a teenager, she published several zines with her friend Lucy, including Moonfork. She and Lucy also formed a band called The Others, which later signed to Duchess Records. Diehl moved to New York and interned at renowned New York recording studios, including Battery and Sound On Sound. One of a small number of female engineers, Diehl’s working credits include Bjork, Busta Rhymes, Dead Prez, G Unit, and Alicia Keys. Diehl currently lives in Los Angeles, where she continues to engineer for albums, as well as do post-production audio work for film and television. She has also expanded into artist management.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated by Kathryn Diehl in 2015; the accession number associated with this gift is 2015.448.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials created and collected by Kathryn Diehl from the early to mid-1990s documenting Diehl’s participation in the Riot Grrrl movement, including newsletters; Riot Grrrl zines; flyers for shows in the Washington, D.C. and Richmond, Virginia areas; and letters to Diehl from individuals such as Kathleen Hanna, Lisa Wildman, and Tobi Vail, predominantly on the subject of Diehl’s zines. The collection also includes masters and copies of Diehl’s own zines Moonfork and Oppression, as well as zines sent to Diehl.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Fanzines.; Feminist music.; Punk culture.; Riot grrrl movement.; Rock music |z United States |y 1991-2000.; Washington (D.C.); Women rock musicians.; Women's rights.; Zines.
- Correspondence: B., Carri, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Beck, Brenda, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: Christina, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Grace, 1994 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: Hanna, Kathleen, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: Jenna, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: Laura, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: Marite, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: Leah, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: Lucy, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: Lynch, Kelli, 1994 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: Mary, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: Michelle, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence: Rakstad, Bekki, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence: Sarah, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence: Vail, Tobi, 1994 October (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence: Wildma, Lisa, 1996 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Correspondence: Witknee, circa 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Pout #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Without #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Lucy #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Factory, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Alien, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Holy Mack'l Dere #7, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Incomplete Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Other Zines, circa 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Moonfork Zine: Flyer, Master Copy, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Moonfork Zine: #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Moonfork Zine: Masters, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Flyers, circa 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Oppression Zine: Masters, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Accidents, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Action Girl Newsletter, #8, 11, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Amazon Anxiety, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- daffodil, #11, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Girl Pride/Blue Ballad, #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- I Kicked a Boy, #1, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Ketchup, #9-10, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Kill Rock Stars, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Make You A Star, #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Night Jar, #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
- One Mint Julep, #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Peach, #4, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Queenie, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Round Flat Records, #27, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Skank, #2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Worthless, #2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Who Cares, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 47)